Lewis Guignard

lewisquignard@gmail.com | 980.875.8786 | LinkedIn

SKILLS

GENERAL

Estimation / Inference Amazon AWS Micro-service Architectures Technical Sales Training / Presentations

PROGRAMMING / DEVOPS

Proficient:

- Python MySql
- Linux (debian/bash/zsh) hjkl
- git gitlab jira

Amateur:

- Matlab Lava C++ Competent:
- R .html/.css/.js

EDUCATION

STANFORD UNIVERSITY

MS ELECTRICAL ENGINEERING

Signal Processing, Data Science June 2016 | Stanford, CA Cum. GPA: 3.7

NCSU

NORTH CAROLINA STATE UNIVERSITY BS PHYSICS 2008-2011 | Raleigh, NC Cum. GPA: 4.0 Valedictorian

COURSEWORK

GRADUATE

Machine Learning Convex Optimization Signal Processing Fourier Analysis Linear Algebra

UNDERGRADUATE

Solid State Physics Modeling / Simulation

INTERESTS

3D Printing | Raspberry Pi | Radio (KM4JQU) | Visualization | Cycling | Photography | Backpacking

SUMMARY

A highly organized, creative data science professional with over 6 years of progressive analysis and prediction experience. Proficiency in full data science pipeline: researching and purchasing data sources, cleansing and quality control, model creation and validation, creating stable and enterprise ready code-base, delivering insights to leadership team. Expert in public speaking and simplifying highly technical concepts. Adept in training and integrating teams of individuals of varying experience.

EXPERIENCE

CORAX CYBER HEAD OF DATA SCIENCE

Mar 2016 - Current | SF, CA

 Builds models to predict frequency and severity of cyber breach and business interruption events • Leads a team of datascientists • Manage estimation projects • Technical sales and speaking • Seek out, negotiate, and ingest new data-sources • Manage 100M daily record ingestion and analysis

UNDERWRITERS LABORATORIES ENGINEER

Oct 2011 - Aug 2014 | Durham, NC

• Critiqued LED Luminaires, modules and power supplies for compliance to relevant UL or IEC international standards. Designed and analyzed test plans for product performance.

HELMHOLTZ ZENTRUM BERLIN VISITING SCIENTIST

Jun 2011 - Sep 2011 | Berlin, Germany

• Experimented in photo-electrochemical systems, semiconductor-electrolyte interfaces and nanoemitters. Focus on photovoltaic science and photo-induced Carbon Dioxide reduction.

PATENTS | PUBLICATIONS | AWARDS

- Patents: US20180069889A1 US20180124092A1
- B. A. Collins, E. Gann, X. He, L. Guignard, C. R. McNeill, H. Ade. Molecular Miscibility of Polymer Fullerene Blends. The Journal of Physical Chemistry Letters 0, 3160-3166
- Machine Learning: Created a 93.1 % accurate musical instrument classifier.
- Lean Six Sigma Green Belt Training | Lean Leader Training
- Phi Beta Kappa | Phi Kappa Phi | Sigma Pi Sigma (National Physics Honor Society)
- Speaker: American Physical Society Meeting 2010 / Net Diligence Santa Monica, CA 2018 / Catastrophe Risk London 2019
- FIRST Robotics volunteer, 2 seasons

RESEARCH

NORTH CAROLINA STATE UNIVERSITY | RESEARCHER

Oct 2008 - Jun 2011 Raleigh, NC

Investigated organic photo-voltaic system dynamics, focusing on efficiency, morphology, material properties. Controlled laboratory equipment, including purchasing, troubleshooting and repairs. Managed several group and individual experiments in parallel. Data collection, analysis, image processing, and presentation.